Guide to the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, 1936-1939
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 4: Microfiche, 1936-1939; (10 boxes)
  - Sing For Your Supper 671, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits (Nielsen, Steiner, Waterbury)".
  - Sing For Your Supper 779, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Rehearsal"
  - Sing For Your Supper 791, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume shots (Nielsen)".
  - Sing For Your Supper 796, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper 849, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits; Marconi, Maxim, Nobel, Watt".
  - Sing For Your Supper 884, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper 896, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper 897, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper 910, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper 923, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper 927, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Paula Lawrence (Helkin)".
  - Sing For Your Supper 928, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume shots Adelphi Theatre (Helkin, Waterbury)".
  - Sing For Your Supper 929, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage sets (Waterbury)".
  - Sing For Your Supper 930, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper 964, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Sing For Your Supper No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - The Singing and the Gold 489, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads Cast Portraits (Arnold)".
  - The Singing and the Gold 509, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Valerie Valaire, portrait (Helkin)".
  - The Singing and the Gold 519, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage sets; production shots (Wernli)".
  - The Singing and the Gold 525, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - Skidding 420, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Washington Square Methodist Church, (Helkin)".
  - Snickering Horses 74, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Experimental theater".
  - Solomon, Miss 830, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portrait; publicity shots".
  - Spirochete 866, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Louis Pasteur, portrait".
  - Spirochete 869, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Illinois, Chicago".
  - Spirochete 924, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Jenner, Pare, Aetatis portraits (Nielsen)".
  - Step This Way, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Vaudeville' poster (Arnold, Helkin)".
  - String Fever 651, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - String Fever 664, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marionette puppeteers".
  - String Fever 683, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Puppeteers (Helkin, Waterbury)".
  - String Fever 746, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - String Fever 747, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
  - String Fever 853, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Ballerina marionette".
  - The Sun and I 57, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage sets".
  - The Sun and I 65, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cast portraits (Cotler, Helkin)".
  - The Sun and I 99A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 103)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots (Haber, Steiner)".
  - The Sun and I 309, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience Adelphi Theatre (Wernli)".
  - The Sun and I 327, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage sets (Steiner)".
  - The Sun and I No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cast portrait, color positive".
  - The Sun Rises in the West No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots California, Los Angeles".
  - Sun Up 319, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Majestic Theatre (Black)".
  - Sweet Land 257, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Lafayette Theatre (Wernli)".
  - Swing It 426, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits Majestic Theatre (Helkin)".
  - Swing It 439, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Studio, cast portraits (Steiner)".
  - Swing It 455, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cast portraits Adelphi Theatre (Helkin)".
  - Swing It 456, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Opening night celebrities Adelphi Theatre (Helkin)".
  - Swing It 458, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Milton Ready, portrait (Helkin)".
  - Swing It 464, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Swing It 475, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Dancers (Helkin)".
  - Swing It 506, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Outside Lafayette Theatre (Wernli)".
  - Swordfish Isle 274, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marionette, audience YMHA (Helkin)".
  - Swordfish Isle 294, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marionette (Wernli)".
  - The Tailor Becomes A Storekeeper 598, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads
  - The Tailor Becomes A Storekeeper 628, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits (Arnold, Steiner)".
  - The Tailor Becomes A Storekeeper 658, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - The Tailor Becomes A Storekeeper 660, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "David Pinsk-author, portrait (Wernli)".
  - The Tailor Becomes A Storekeeper 662, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Morris Weissman, portrait (Steiner)".
  - Taking the Air 76, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Taking the Air 198, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Vaudeville Jamaica Arena (Haber)".
  - Talbert Choir 397, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "POrtrait Nora Bayes Theatre (Waterbury)".
  - Tamiris, Helen 107, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Tamiris, Helen 442, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Receiving prize, Dance Magazine, Nora Bayes Theatre (Arnold)".
  - Tea and Algebra Mystery Box 422, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama YWCA, Bedford Avenue (Black)".
  - Terrible Meek 226, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots M.E. Church; New York, Elmhurst, (Wernli)".
  - There's None of Them Perfect 353, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Riverside Presbyterian Church, (Arnold)".
  - The Three Sisters 919, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Tobias and the Angel 374, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Provincetown Playhouse (Wernli)".
  - Toby Tyler's Circus 365, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Mrionette (Monoson)".
  - Toby Tyler's Circus 383, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "School girls and puppets Public School #17 (Arnold)".
  - Tom Thumb Circus 272, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume portraits (Wernli)".
  - Tons of Money 419, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan Hebrew Orphan Asylum (Wernli)".
  - Tons of Money 428, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan, audience Roosevelt Park (Waterbury)".
  - Tons of Money 431, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience, production shots Washington Square Park (Monoson)".
  - The Toy Shop 388, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Children's theater Public School #28 (Waterbury)".
  - The Toy Shop 852, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Children's theater Public School #155".
  - Treasure Hunt 266, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume portrait Princess Theatre (Helkin)".
  - Treasure Island 639, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Model sets (Waterbury)".
  - Treasure Island 685, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Treasure Island 689, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume pictures (Waterbury, Wernli)".
  - Treasure Island 691, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Jackie Cooper Hotel Warwick (Helkin, Waterbury)".
  - Treasure Island 723, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan Pier 17; New York, Staten Island (Helkin, Waterbury)".
  - Treasure Island 801, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Trial by Jury 125, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Trial by Jury 131, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume portraits; audience (Balery)".
  - The Trial of Dr. Beck 468, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - The Trial of Dr. Beck 469, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Copy of photographs (Helkin)".
  - The Trial of Dr. Beck 470, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - The Trial of Dr. Beck 473, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Delegation Maxine Elliott's Theatre (Wernli)".
  - The Trial of Mary Dugan 2, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Fingerprints".
  - Triple A Plowed Under 79, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production; backstage".
  - Triple A Plowed Under 80, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Trojan Incident 619, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Eleanor Eden, portrait (Nielsen)".
  - Trojan Incident 625, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Studio portraits (Arnold, Steiner)".
  - Trojan Incident 635, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Colfax Sanderson, portrait (Waterbury)".
  - Trojan Incident 648, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Tamiris, Helen (Nielsen)".
  - Trojan Incident 659, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Poster St. James Theatre".
  - Trojan Incident 666, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Wallingford-composer, portrait (Steiner)".
  - Trojan Incident 672, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marcel Rousseau (Steiner)".
  - Trojan Incident 681, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "PRoduction shots (Helkin)".
  - Trojan Incident 697, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Little girl, portrait (Steiner)".
  - Turpentine 81, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits; production shots".
  - Two Gentlemen of the Bench 263, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Uliman, B. 820, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Studio portrait".
  - Unto Such Glory 387, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Ritz Theatre (Wernli)".
  - The Valiant Tailor 301, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Vaudeville 149, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Jack Mason, portrait".
  - Vaudeville 157, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Matt Shelvey, portrait (Wernli)".
  - Vaudeville 173, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Office (Helkin)".
  - Vaudeville 250, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Frances Everett, portrait (Steiner)".
  - Vaudeville 268, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Unit 1B (Wernli)".
  - Vaudeville 270, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Unit 3B (Helkin)".
  - Vaudeville 271, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Unit 2B (Monoson)".
  - Vaudeville 328, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Unit 4B (Colter)".
  - Vaudeville 330, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Unit 4B, 5B cast portraits (Cltler)".
  - Vaudeville 472, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Heads of cast; J.Melino, B. Hibbitt, S. Lewis, M. Lloyd (Waterbury)".
  - Vaudeville 559, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Unit 5B (Wernli)".
  - Vaudeville 571, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marquee (Helkin)".
  - Vaudeville No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Traveling troupe Prison; District of Columbia Washington".
  - Walk Together Children 83, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Lafayette Theatre".
  - Washington Square No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Map".
  - Watson, Morris 170, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caricature (Wernli)".
  - Watson, Morris 341, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portrait (Black)".
  - We Live and Laugh 126, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Yiddish, cast portraits".
  - We Live and Laugh 191, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Crowd Shots (Wernli)".
  - What Price America 436, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Cropey Avenue Methodist Church, (Monoson)".
  - Whistling in the Dark 768, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan, audience Crotona Park (Helkin)".
  - White Iris 702, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Institute for the Blind (Wernli)".
  - Winter 262, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - The Woman of Destiny 110, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Works Progress Administration 87, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Signs".
  - Works Progress Administration 178, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Sewing project (Haber)".
  - Works Progress Administration 223, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Poster Grand Central Station (Helkin)".
  - Work Progress Administration 224, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Work Progress Administration No #A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Work Progress Administration No #B, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Historical records".
  - World Tour 174, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - World's Fair 948, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Workers assembling display".
  - Young Tramps 23, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Dance Group".
  - Young Tramps 57, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Model sets".
  - Young Tramps 122, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
  - Young Tramps 137, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 104)
- Series 5: Printing Materials, 1936-1939; (8 boxes)
  This series is split into three subseries: Zinc Plates and Mats, Woodblocks, and Mimeographs.This series contains zinc plates, mats, mimeographs and woodblocks that were used in the production of publications for the Federal Theater Project. The series is arranged alphabetically starting with productions and then going into portraits.
  - Subseries 5.1: Zinc Plates and Mats, 1930s; (4 boxes)
    Zinc plates and mats created out of the plates to use in print production.
    - 9 Pine Street, circa 1936-1939 (Box 105, Folder 1)
      Matrix/Mat inside a white sleeve with pencil writing. In pencil: "Federal Theatre", "9 Pine Street", "Zinc Plate + Matrix".
    - Alice in Wonderland, circa 1936-1939 (Box 105, Folder 2)